Parham **Alvani**

PHD STUDENT · BACKEND DEVELOPER

□ (+98) 939-09-09-540 | ■ parham.alvani@gmail.com | ♠ https://1995parham.me | ☑ 1995parham | ﴾ 1995parham | 🖹 parham-alvani | 🗞 parham.alvani | № 1995parham

"I have a dream"

Summary.

Current Backend Enginner at ride hailing company Snapp. 3+ years experience specializing in the backend development, system design. Super nerd who loves Vim, Linux and OS X and enjoys to customize all of the development environment. Interested in Network Function Virtualization, Optimization, Software Defined Networking.

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES AND TECHNOLOGIES

- Golang & C (Expert)
- AMD64 Assembly (Expert)
- Nodejs & Python (Specialist)
- Laravel (Skilled)
- Angular (Specialist)
- Ubuntu, Docker & Kubernetes (Expert)
- Rust (Beginner)

NETWORKING TOOLS AND PROTOCOLS

- · OpenFlow1.3, OpenFlow1.5
- · ONOS Platform, FloodLight, Ryu
- Mininet

Work Experience

Iranian Telecommunication Reseach Center (ITRC)

Tehran, Iran Summer 2016

TRAINEE

• Designed and implemented the home automation solutions using the Raspberry Pi

System Architect & Software Engineer

Jul. 2017 - Jun. 2019

• Designed the scalable IoT Platform that can handle 1K rps with Golang

IoT Working Group of Amirkabir University of Technology

• Run services with Docker on bare-metals and monitored them using Prometheus

Snapp! Tehran, Iran

Backend Engineer Feb. 2019 - Present

• Developed location based system that handles high load

University of Technology

• Designed and Developed surge pricing system that consumes 6K messages per second with Golang

Honors & Awards

ACADEMIC

2016	4th Place , Semi-Final National Scientific Olympiad in Computer Engineering	Tehran, Iran
2016	10th Place, Final National Scientific Olympiad in Computer Engineering	Tehran, Iran

COMPETITION

Fall 2014

Spring 2016	2nd Place, 3nd National Digital Design Contest of Iran ASIC League	Tehran, Iran
Spring 2016	3rd Place , 3nd National Digital Design Contest of Iran CoDesign League	Tehran, Iran
Spring 2015	3rd Place , 2nd National Digital Design Contest of Iran CoDesign League	Tehran, Iran
Fall 2014	3rd Place , 14th Amirkabir ACM International Collegiate Programming Contest (ICPC)	Tehran, Iran
Eall 2014	Merit Medal, 39th Asia Regional ACM International Collegiate Programming Contest (ICPC) in Sharif	Tohran Iran

May 14, 2020 Powered by LETEXAND AWESOMECV

HIGH SCHOOL

2012	Semi-finalist, National Mathematics and Computer Olympiads	Tehran, Iran
2011	Finalist, National Mathematics and Computer Olympiads	Tehran, Iran
2010	Finalist, National Mathematics and Computer Olympiads	Tehran, Iran
2010	Merit Award, International Mathematics Competition (IMC)	Icheon, S.Korea

Teaching Experience

Principles of Computer and Programming

TEACHING ASSISTANT

Fall 2014, Fall 2015, Fall 2016, Fall 2017, Fall 2018, Spring 2019, Fall 2019

Advanced Programming

TEACHING ASSISTANT

Spring 2015, Spring 2016, Spring 2018

Discrete Mathematics

TEACHING ASSISTANT

Spring 2015

Introduction to Python Programming

INSTRUCTOR

Spring 2015

Principles of Database Design

TEACHING ASSISTANT

Spring 2016, Spring 2017

Microprocessor I

TEACHING ASSISTANT

Spring 2016, Spring 2018, Fall 2018, Spring 2019

Engineering Statistics and Probability

TEACHING ASSISTANT

Spring 2016

Introduction to Golang Programming

INSTRUCTOR

Spring 2016

IoT & IPv6

SPEAKER

Spring 2016

Principles of Database Design

TEACHING ASSISTANT

Fall 2016

Data Structure Design

TEACHING ASSISTANT

Fall 2016, Fall 2017

Computer Architecture

TEACHING ASSISTANT

Spring 2017

Introduction to IoT Platform

SPEAKER

Spring 2017

Golang, The Future of C

SPEAKER

Spring 2017

Amirkabir University of Technology

Under Supervision of Prof. Bakhshi

Amirkabir University of Technology

Under Supervision of Prof. Noorhosseini

Amirkabir University of Technology

Under Supervision of Prof. Fallah

7th Amirkahir Linux Festival

Amirkabir University of Technology

Under Supervision of Prof. Momtazi

Amirkabir University of Technology

Under Supervision of Prof.

Homayounpour

Amirkahir University of Technology

Under Supervision of Prof. Amir Haeri

8th Amirkahir Linux Festival

otti Amirkabir Linux restivat

8th Amirkabir Linux Festival

mirkahir University of Technology

Under Supervision of Prof. Amir Haeri

Amirkabir University of Technology

Under Supervision of Prof. Dehghan

Amirkabir University of Technology

Under Supervision of Prof. Shiri

2nd Iran IoT Conference

9th Amirkabir Linux Festival

I1820, The IoT Platform

SPEAKER

Spring 2017

Advanced Python Programming

INSTRUCTOR

Summer 2017

An Introduction to IoT Platforms

INSTRUCTOR

Summer 2017

Computer Networks

Under Supervision of Prof. Sabaei

Under Supervision of Prof. Sabaei

Under Supervision of Prof. Noorhosseini

Under Supervision of Prof. Zarandi

Under Supervision of Prof.

Homayounpour

Fall 2019

Fall 2017

2015-2017

Spring 2016

TEACHING ASSISTANT

Spring 2018, Fall 2018, Spring 2019

Microprocessor Lab

INSTRUCTOR

Spring 2018

Computer Networks Lab

INSTRUCTOR

Spring 2018, Fall 2018, Spring 2019

Advanced Programming Workshop

INSTRUCTOR

Spring 2018

Operating System Lab

INSTRUCTOR

Fall 2018, Fall 2019

Introduction to Programming Workshop

INSTRUCTOR

Fall 2019

Under Supervision of Prof. Bakhshi

Research Experience

SFC Requests Admission Control by Considering VNFMs

MAXIMIZE PROFIT BASED ON AN OPTIMIZATION PROBLEM FOR ACCEPTING SFCS AND CONSIDERS VNFMS FOR THEM

• M.Sc. Project

General purpose IoT platform, design for scalability

RESEARCH AND DEVELOP DISTRIBUTED, DOCKER BASED IOT PLATFORM NAMED 11820

· B.Sc. Project

Department-wide platform for IoT and building management systems

RESEARCH ON DIFFERENT OPERATING SYSTEMS, FRAMEWORKS AND PROTOCOL STACKS IN IOT

• Amirkabir IoT Labratory (AoLab) resource are available here

Resource Provisioning in Sotfware Defined Networking

• This research was done for Research Method and Technical Writings course

Education

Energy Atomic High School

DIPLOMA OF MATH & PHYSICS Sep. 2009 — Sep. 2013

• GPA: 19.45/20

Amirkabir University of Technology

B.Sc. IN COMPUTER SOFTWARE ENGINEERING Sep. 2013 — Sep. 2017

• GPA: 18.94/20

Amirkabir University of Technology

Amirkabir University of Technology

M.Sc. in Computer Network

• GPA: 18.94/20

Sep. 2017 — Sep. 2019

Ph.D. IN COMPUTER NETWORK

• GPA: N/A

Sep. 2019 — Sep. 2023

Extracurricular Activity

Linux Festival

SCIENTIFIC DIRECTOR

Spring 2016, Spring 2017

- Seleted the presentors for event
- · Coordinated the technical aspects of event

AUT ICPC

HEAD OF TECHNICAL TEAM

Fall 2016, Fall 2017, Fall 2018

- · Setup the judge server
- · Coordinated the clients configuration and setup

Amirkabir Programming League

HEAD OF TECHNICAL TEAM

- · Setup the judge server
- · Coordinated the clients configuration and setup

Certificate

- CompTIA Network+
- Supporting Windows 8.1 (70–688)
- Installing and Configuring Windows Server 2012 (70–410)
- Administering Windows Server 2012 (70–411)
- Configuring Advanced Windows Server 2012 Services (70–412)
- Designing and Implementing a Server Infrastructure (70–413)
- Implementing an Advanced Server Infrastructure (70–414)
- LPIC-1 (101-102)
- LPIC-2 (201–202)
- Cisco CCENT
- VMware vSphere: Install, Configure, Manage
- · VMware vSphere: Optimize and Scale

Spring 2019